Guide to the Laura Brownell Collier Papers, 1867-1949
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Laura Brownell Collier Papers
1867-1949
Collier, Laura Brownell
1.8 cubic feet (5 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The collection consists of correspondence, notes, diaries, and other material relating to and created by Laura Brownell Collier (VC 1874), covering her time at Vassar and beyond.
Biographical Note
Laura Brownell Collier was born on January 27, 1851 in Williston, Vermont. A member of a prominent New England family, she was descended from Governor William Bradford and John and Priscilla Alden. Laura's father, Chauncey Wells Brownell, was prominent lawyer and Vermont state senator, and her mother, Laura Chapin Higbee Brownell, had been head of the Williston Academy.
At the age of 13 Laura began teaching in a one-room school in Williston and later taught in the Burlington, Vermont public schools for $1.50 a week. She entered Vassar College as a senior and was graduated in 1874 as a member of Phi Beta Kappa. After Vassar, she taught at Abbot Academy in Andover, Massachusetts for three years, and then studied at Berlin University from 1877 to 1878.
In 1882, Laura married John Austin Collier, a research chemist who worked on experiments involving sorghum, rice production, and milling. They then moved to Brooklyn, New York where Laura found a job teaching Latin at Packer Collegiate Institute. They had two daughters, Elizabeth and Katharine, who attended both Packer and later, Vassar College. From 1902 until 1911, John was the manager of the Vermont and Arizona Copper Company, which was located in Arizona, although Laura and the girls remained in New York. Laura was widowed on September 11, 1920.
Active in various historical and social organizations, Laura was a member of the Alden Kindred Association, the Meridian Club, the League of Women Voters, and other groups concerning the antiwar and woman suffrage movements. She took pride in the fact that she voted at every regular and special election. Laura also wrote a number of editorials for the New York Press, on topics ranging from the Mexican Revolution to the College Settlement movement.
In 1942 she moved back to Vermont with her younger daughter, Katharine, where she remained until her death in 1949.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of correspondence, notes, diaries, and other material relating to and created by Laura Brownell Collier (VC 1874), covering her time at Vassar and beyond. Like both the Elizabeth Brownell Collier Papers Katharine Brownell Collier Papers, the papers of Laura Brownell Collier tend to be weak on substance and superficial in areas. For example, there is little or no information concerning her teaching career or the program she initiated between Packer Collegiate Institute and Vassar College. The collection's strength lies in the amount of personal correspondence, notes and diaries kept by Laura Brownell Collier, as well as newspaper articles written by her.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Researchers interested in more of the personal aspects of Laura Brownell Collier's life are encouraged to examine the Class of 1874 Bulletins, as well as the Alumnae/i Biographical Files in the Archives and Special Collections Library:
Laura Brownell File, Alumnae/i Biographical Files
The papers of Laura's two daughters, Elizabeth Brownell Collier, VC 1906, and Katharine Brownell Collier, VC 1908, are also available for research:
Elizabeth Brownell Collier Papers
Katharine Brownell Collier Papers
Subject Headings
Names:
Collier, Elizabeth Brownell; Collier, John A.; Collier, Katharine Brownell; Brownell, Chauncey W.; Brownell, Laura Higbee
Organizations:
Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae
Document Types:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Diaries; Photographs; Printed ephemera
VCL Categories:
Family; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Madeleine Amodio, June 2011. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, June 2025.
Custodial History
This collection was brought to the Vassar College Libraries in the early 1980s by Elizabeth Daniels, the Vassar College Historian, who received them from Mr. Lincoln Brownell, Laura Brownell Collier's closest living relative.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Lincoln Brownell, through Elizabeth Daniels, circa 1980-1984. Received in three accessions.
Series List
- Series I. PERSONAL CORREPSONDENCE, 1879-1947
- Series II. EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS, 1867-1942
- Series III. ORGANIZATIONS, 1929-1943
- Series IV. NOTES AND NOTEBOOKS, 1881-1943
- Series V. PERIODICALS AND NEWSPAPER ARTICLES, 1874-1949
- Series VI. PERSONAL BUSINESS, 1877-1941
- Series VII. PHOTOGRAPHS, 1874-1934
- Series VIII. POSTCARDS, 1877-1912
- Series IX. MEMORABILIA, 1882-1945
Container List
- SERIES I. PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1879-1947
  - Correspondence to Laura Brownell Collier (LBC)
    - Collier, Elizabeth Brownell (daughter of LBC), 1908-1937; (10 items) (Folder 1.1)
    - Collier, John A. (husband of LBC), 1908; (3 items) (Folder 1.2)
    - Collier, Katharine Brownell (daughter of LBC), circa 1904-1908; (2 items) (Folder 1.3)
    - Collier, Katharine Brownell, 1907-1909; (14 items) (Folder 1.4)
    - Collier, Katharine Brownell, 1936-1942; (3 items) (Folder 1.5)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1880-1884; (10 items) (Folder 1.6)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1903-1921; (7 items) (Folder 1.7)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1923-1938; (13 items) (Folder 1.8)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1939-1947; (8 items) (Folder 1.9)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; (5 items) (Folder 1.10)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; (9 items) (Folder 1.11)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; (3 items) (Folder 1.12)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated (Folder 4.2)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated (Folder 4.3)
    - Collier, Katharine Brownell - Correspondence to KBC, undated (Folder 4.9)
  - Correspondence from Laura Brownell Collier
    - Brownell, Chauncey W. (brother of LBC), 1932, undated; (5 items) (Folder 1.13)
    - Brownell, Laura Higbee (mother of LBC), 1879, undated; (3 items) (Folder 1.14)
    - Collier, John A., 1912; (1 item) (Folder 1.15)
    - Collier, Katharine and Elizabeth, 1923; (1 item) (Folder 1.16)
    - Various friends (form letter), 1941; (1 item) (Folder 1.17)
    - Letters From LBC, undated (Folder 4.1)
- SERIES II. EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS, 1867-1942
  - Burlington Public Schools
    - Correspondence from the Superintendent (annotated by LBC), 1867-1868; (4 items) (Folder 1.18)
    - Correspondence from the Superintendent, 1869-870; (7 items) (Folder 1.19)
  - Vassar College
    - Booklet-Associate Alumnae Annual Meeting, 1922; (TS, 19 p.) (Folder 1.20)
    - Report of the Associate Alumnae (annotated by LBC), 1929-1930; (TS, 69 p.) (Folder 1.21)
    - Vassar Quarterly (annotated by LBC), 1931 Feb; (TS, 90 p.) (Folder 1.22)
    - Address given by LBC at an Alumnae Luncheon, 1934 Jun 9; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 1.23)
    - Letter from President MacCracken, 1934 Jun 21; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 1.24)
    - Letter from Allan Richardson, Comptroller, re: Brownell-Collier Scholarship Fund, 1937 Dec 17; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 1.25)
    - Alumnae questionnaire, 1939; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 1.26)
    - Commencement week invitation (annotated by LBC), 1941; (1 item) (Folder 1.27)
    - Draft of a speech by LBC re: VC, undated; (MS, 2 p., 1 draft, 1 fragment) (Folder 1.28)
    - Vassar College, undated (Folder 4.12)
  - Abbott Academy
    - The Abbot Courant (annotated by LBC), 1881 Nov; (TS, 48 p.) (Folder 1.29)
    - Memorial to Philena McKeen, Principal of Abbot Academy, 1898 May; (TS, 58 p.) (Folder 1.30)
    - Abbot Academy Club constitution (annotated by LBC), 1914; (TS/MS, 10 p.) (Folder 1.31)
    - Letter from Alumnae Association incl. draft of LBC's reply, 1923 Jun 5; (3 items) (Folder 1.32)
    - Abbot Academy prospectus or circular, circa 1940s; (TS, 23 p.) (Folder 1.33)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell- Abbot Academy, undated (Folder 4.4)
  - Acadia University
    - Acadia Bulletin, 1934 Apr; (TS, 24 p.) (Folder 1.34)
    - Correspondence from the Office of the President (annotated by LBC with an explanation of connection to Acadia), 1935; (2 items) (Folder 1.35)
    - Acadia University Calendar, 1935-1936; (TS, 164 p.) (Folder 1.36)
  - Miscellaneous Institutions
    - Princeton University Commencement program (annotated by LBC), 1913; (TS, 11 p.) (Folder 1.37)
    - Hamilton College Bulletin (see p. 12 for obituary of John Collier), 1938; (TS, 51 p.) (Folder 1.38)
    - Pratt Institute library card, 1942; (1 item) (Folder 1.39)
- SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS, 1929-1943
  - Alden Kindred of America
    - Roster notes, undated; (TS, 6 p.) (Folder 1.40)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell - Alden Kindred and Clinton Ave. Congregational Church, undated (Folder 4.5)
  - American Red Cross
    - Correspondence and program (annotated by LBC), 1942; (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 1.41)
  - Brooklyn Church and Mission Federation
    - Correspondence (annotated by LBC), 1933-1934; (3 items) (Folder 1.42)
    - Pamphlet (annotated by LBC), 1942; (1 item) (Folder 1.43)
  - Brooklyn Colony of the National Society of New England Women
    - By-laws, undated; (TS, 20 p.) (Folder 1.44)
    - Programs (annotated by LBC), 1936-1938; (4 items) (Folder 1.45)
  - Clinton Avenue Congregational Church
    - Church bulletins, 1929; (TS, 10 p.) (Folder 1.46)
  - Meridian Club
    - Correspondence, 1938-1940; (3 items) (Folder 1.47)
    - Constitution, 1930; (TS, 12 p.) (Folder 1.49)
    - Membership list and receipt (annotated by LBC), 1938-1942; (TS, 7 p.) (Folder 1.49)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell- Meridian Club, undated (Folder 4.6)
  - Phi Beta Kappa
    - Correspondence, 1940-1942; (4 items) (Folder 1.50)
    - Publications (some annotated by LBC), 1937-1943, undated; (14 items) (Folder 1.51)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, undated (Folder 4.13)
  - Woman Suffrage Party
    - Sash, yellow with black letters, "Woman Suffrage Party", undated; (1 item) (Map Case - Drawer 37)
  - Women's University Club (KBC)
    - Collier, Katharine Brownell - Women's University Club, undated (Folder 4.10)
  - Miscellaneous Organizations
    - Miscellaneous Organizations, undated (Folder 4.14)
- SERIES IV. NOTES AND NOTEBOOKS, 1881-1943
  - Notes Written by Laura Brownell Collier
    - To S.A.B. and C.W.B. Compensations (brothers of LBC), 1922 Apr; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.52)
    - A Priceless Heritage, 1935; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.53)
    - All Shall Have Joy, undated; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.54)
    - The Blizzard, undated; (TS, 2 p., 2 drafts) (Folder 1.55)
    - Contrasts, undated; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.56)
    - The Eternal Conflict/High Tide, undated; (TS, 4 p., 4 drafts) (Folder 1.57)
    - In The Park, undated; (TS, 3 p., 3 drafts) (Folder 1.58)
    - Just to say..., undated; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.59)
    - Lo! First comes our..., undated; (TS, 4 p., 1 draft (?)) (Folder 1.60)
    - Nature's Work, undated; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.61)
    - The Recluse, undated; (TS, 3 p., 3 drafts) (Folder 1.62)
    - Suppressed Desires, undated; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.63)
    - Threescore and Ten, undated; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.64)
    - Training Tells (short story), 1917; (TS, 9 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.65)
    - An Interesting Old Plant (bryophyllum), undated; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.66)
    - Autobiographical notes, undated; (MS, 4 fragments) (Folder 1.67)
    - Mrs. Elizabeth Collier (upon the death of), 1889; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.68)
    - Woman's place is in the home..., undated; (MS, 2 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.69)
    - Fragments of verses, undated; (MS, 10 fragments) (Folder 1.70)
    - By Collier, Laura Brownell: Manuscript (Memoir) and Letters, undated (Folder 4.7)
    - Written by KBC/LBC, undated (Folder 4.15)
  - Notes Written by Others
    - Sketches: ink/pencil artist unknown, undated; (5 items) (Folder 1.71)
    - This is the... author: John Gadge (?) (facsimile), [1564]; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.72)
    - I knew the trees would leaf... author: Martha Dickinson Bianchi, 1942; (TS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.73)
    - Guilty or Not Guilty author: Leah Sinsky, undated; (MS, 4 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.74)
    - Oh Laura Collier bless your heart..., 1941; (MS, 3 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.75)
    - Love suffereth long... author unknown, undated; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.76)
    - Magnum iter... author unknown, undated; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.77)
    - O true and tried... author unknown, undated; (MS, 1 p., 1 draft) (Folder 1.78)
    - Note cards with verses, 1903-1905; (MS, 18 items) (Folder 1.79)
    - Note cards with verses, undated; (MS, 28 items) (Folder 1.80)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated; (MS, 17 fragments) (Folder 1.81)
  - Notebooks of Laura Brownell Collier
    - South Hall Chronicles diary while at Abbot Academy and beyond, 1881-1903, 1943; (MS, 113 p., incl. enclosures) (Folder 1.82)
    - Calendar, 1910; (no handwritten notations) (Folder 1.83)
    - Travel Notes L.B. Collier, 1912; (MS, 61 p.) (Folder 1.84)
    - Daily Calendar (removed from metal stand), 1943; (MS, 322 p.) (Folder 1.85)
    - Notebook, probably not LBC's handwriting, undated; (MS, 118 p.) (Folder 1.86)
- SERIES V. PERIODICALS AND NEWSPAPER ARTICLES, 1874-1949
  - Periodicals
    - Massachusetts Teacher (see p. 490), 1874 Dec; (TS, 41 p.) (Folder 2.1)
    - Keith Johnson's Political Atlas, circa 1870s; (1 book) (Folder 2.2)
    - Vocal Culture and Selections for Reading, undated; (TS, 11 p.) (Folder 2.3)
    - The Chicago Amateur, undated; (TS, 8 p.) (Folder 2.4)
    - History Facts and Worth of the Bible, undated; (TS, 32 p.) (Folder 2.5)
  - Newspaper Articles Written by Laura Brownell Collier
    - op-ed articles source: New York Press, 1915 Jul-Aug; (TS, 9 p.) (Folder 2.6)
    - op-ed articles source: New York Press, 1915 Sep-Dec; (TS, 15 p.) (Folder 2.7)
    - op-ed articles source: New York Press, 1916; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 2.8)
    - letter to editor; published poem source: Burlington [VT] Free Press, 1937-1942; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 2.9)
    - Popular Humorists of the Decade; op-ed articles sources unknown, undated; (TS, 8 p.) (Folder 2.10)
  - Newspaper Articles About Laura Brownell Collier
    - The Women's College Alumnae Associations source: Harper's Bazar, 1896; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 5.1)
    - Articles re: donation to Canastota Hospital, NY, 1920-1921; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 2.11)
    - Article re: LBC's Vassar College semi-centennial reunion, circa 1924; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 5.1)
    - Articles re: travel, advice, and awards of LBC ,(some annotated by LBC), 1930-1942; (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 2.12)
    - Obituaries for LBC, 1949 Dec; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 2.13)
    - Obituaries - Clark, Kate Upson, 1935 Feb; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 2.14)
    - Obituaries - Collier, Helen M. (sister-in-law of LBC), 1903 Sep; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 2.15)
    - Obituaries - Darling, Frank W., 1941 Feb; (TS, 10 p.) (Folder 2.16)
    - Obituaries - Dinsmoor, Alice, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 2.17)
    - Obituaries - Frost, Elinor White, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 2.18)
    - Obituaries - Kimball, Mrs. James P., undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 2.19)
    - Obituaries - Montague, Amy Collier (niece of LBC), 1941; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 2.20)
  - Articles About Honorable Guy Charteris
    - Articles re: Guy Charteris (shipmate of LBC in 1912), 1912-1923; (TS, 6 p.) (Folder 2.21)
    - Articles re: Guy Charteris (shipmate of LBC in 1912), undated; (2 items) (Folder 5.1)
    - Articles re: Guy Charteris, undated; (TS, 8 p.) (Folder 2.22)
  - Miscellaneous Articles
    - Miscellaneous articles, 1936-1942; (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 2.23)
    - Miscellaneous articles, undated; (TS, 15 p.) (Folder 2.24)
    - Newspaper Articles, undated (Folder 4.16)
- SERIES VI. PERSONAL BUSINESS, 1877-1941
  - Letter from The Republican re: publishing LBC, 1877; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 2.25)
  - Correspondence re: memorial to John A. Collier, Canastota Memorial Hospital, 1921; (MS/TS, 3 p.) (Folder 2.26)
  - Correspondence and account statements from White, Weld and Co., a Wall Street firm, 1940-1941; (TS, 8 p.) (Folder 2.27)
  - Bills and receipts, 1941, undated; (10 items) (Folder 2.28)
  - Canceled checks, 1939-1941; (2 items) (Folder 2.29)
  - Business cards, undated; (3 items) (Folder 2.30)
  - Notes re: financial matters, undated; (MS, 3 fragments) (Folder 2.31)
- SERIES VII. PHOTOGRAPHS, 1874-1934
  - Photographs of Laura Brownell Collier
    - Portrait of LBC seated, holding a book photographer: Sarony's, circa 1874; (1 item) (Folder 2.32)
    - Portrait of LBC profile, seated at desk photographer unknown, circa 1898; (1 item) (Folder 2.33)
    - Portrait of LBC - head and shoulders -head and torso wearing white dress photographer: Curtis Bell, Inc., 1924; (2 items) (Folder 5.2)
    - Photo of LBC full length, standing sideways photographer unknown ref. number 3.599, 1931; (1 item) (Folder 2.34)
    - Portrait of LBC head and torso, wearing dark dress photographer: Alice Boughton ref. number 3.598, 1931; (1 item) (Folder 2.35)
    - Portrait of LBC head and torso, wearing dark dress photographer: Alice Boughton ref. number 3.598, undated; (1 Item) (Folder 5.2)
    - Portrait of LBC with Peace Committee of Federation of Protestant Churches, 1933; (1 item ) (Folder 2.36)
    - Portrait of LBC with Peace Committee of Federation of Protestant Churches, undated; (1 item) (Folder 5.2)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell with Helen Jackson Sellers, VC 1874, at their Vassar College 60th reunion, 1934; (1 item) (Folder 2.37)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell with unidentified man and woman in a wooded area ref. numbers 6.560 and 6.561, undated; (2 items) (Folder 2.38)
  - Photographs of Friends and Family
    - Collier, Helen M., undated; (1 item) (Folder 1.87)
    - Marvin, Mary, undated; (1 item) (Folder 1.88)
    - Prentiss, Mrs. George H., undated; (1 item) (Folder 1.89)
    - Stanton, Maggie, undated; (1 item) (Folder 1.90)
    - Talmage, David, 1883, undated; (2 items) (Folder 1.91)
    - VC: Avery, Alida; Backus, Truman J.; Farrar, Charles, undated; (3 items) (Folder 1.92)
    - VC photo album of students and faculty, [circa 1874] (Folder 1.93)
  - Photographs of Trips Taken by Laura Brownell Collier
    - View of Lake George, 1882; (1 item) (Folder 1.94)
    - Adirondacks - 7th Lake, Fulton, Chain, Wheeler's Camp, 1906; (14 items) (Folder 1.95)
    - Niagara Falls, 1909; (15 items) (Folder 1.96)
    - Canastota Memorial Hospital, 1920; (3 items) (Folder 1.97)
    - Mt. Vernon and Washington, DC, undated; (4 items) (Folder 1.98)
    - Sleepy Hollow [NY], undated; (2 items) (Folder 1.99)
    - Miscellaneous photos of houses, undated; (2 items) (Folder 1.100)
  - Photographs of Artwork
    - Photos of paintings, unmarked, artists unknown, undated; (2 items) (Folder 1.101)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Folder 4.17)
- SERIES VIII. POSTCARDS, 1877-1912
  - Trips Taken by Laura Brownell Collier
    - European trip-German landscapes, 1877-1878; (4 items) (Folder 1.102)
    - European trip-German monuments, 1877-78, 1877-1878; (4 items) (Folder 1.103)
    - European trip-famous Germans, 1877-1878; (7 items) (Folder 1.104)
    - European trip-Masterpieces in the Dresden Gallery (annotated by LBC), 1877-1878; (8 items) (Folder 1.105)
    - European trip-famous Europeans, 1877-1878; (4 items) (Folder 3.1)
    - European trip-view of Rome, 1878; (1 item) (Folder 3.2)
    - Trip to United Kingdom-view of ship, 1912; (1 item) (Folder 3.3)
    - Trip to United Kingdom-view of Ireland, 1912; (1 item) (Folder 3.4)
    - Trip to United Kingdom-views of England, 1912; (2 items) (Folder 3.5)
    - Trip to United Kingdom-Investiture of the Prince of Wales, 1912; (3 items) (Folder 3.6)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Folder 4.18)
  - Landscapes
    - Long Island and ocean views, undated; (3 items) (Folder 3.7)
  - Buildings
    - Cazenovia Seminary-attended by John A. Collier, undated; (6 items) (Folder 3.8)
    - Brownell Homestead, Williston, VT, undated; (1 item) (Folder 3.9)
    - Miscellaneous houses, undated; (2 items) (Folder 3.10)
- SERIES IX. MEMORABILIA, 1882-1945
  - Travel Information
    - Brochure of Adirondacks, circa 1906; (TS, 7 p.) (Folder 3.11)
    - Niagara Falls information, circa 1909; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 3.12)
    - United Kingdom trip: brochures and programs re: Atlantic Transport Lines, 1912; (5 items) (Folder 3.13)
    - U.K. trip: Ireland information, 1912; (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 3.14)
    - U.K. trip: Scotland information (some annotated by LBC), 1912; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 3.15)
    - U.K. trip: England information, 1912; (TS, 20 p.) (Folder 3.16)
    - Miscellaneous travel information, undated; (4 items) (Folder 3.17)
  - Miscellaneous Memorabilia
    - Marriage certificate: John Austin Collier and Laura Higbee Brownell, 1882; (1 item) (Folder 3.18)
    - Programs, 1910-1912, undated; (4 items) (Folder 3.19)
    - Material re: World War II, including war ration booklets, ca. 1940-45, circa 1940-1945; (3 items) (Folder 3.20)
    - Material re: Brooklyn area; LBC's Senators, undated; (3 items) (Folder 3.21)
    - World War I poster "Imprunt National 1918 Societe General Pour nou rendre entiere…,", circa 1918; (1 item) [MISSING as of June 2025] (Map Case)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell - Miscellaneous, undated (Folder 4.8)
    - Collier, Katharine Brownell - Political Material, undated (Folder 4.11)